Guide to the Asa and Elna Spaulding Papers, 1909-1997 and undated, bulk 1935-1983 RL.01240
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Asa Spaulding Subgroup, 1909-1984 and undated, 331 boxes
  - Writings and Speeches Series, 1931-1981, bulk late 1950s-late 1970s, 17 boxes
    - 'In the Fullness of Time,' a Prince of Peace: A 1977 Prelude to Christmas and related papers, 1977 Dec. 18 and 24, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-8)
    - In Retrospect and In Prospect, 1963, 2 drafts (Box AWS-8)
    - Instructors with Visions of the Future: Essentials to Good Education, press release, undated (Box AWS-8)
    - Instructors with Visions of the Future: Vital to Quality Education for Tomorrow! undated (Box AWS-8)
    - Insurance Lessons Drawn from the Incident of the 'Mighty Mo' and 'Mighty Mo' and Life Insurance, 1960 Sept. 15 and Oct. 15 (Box AWS-8)
    - Insurance โ A Tree for All Seasons and Purposes, 1980 (Box AWS-8)
    - Interaction: Challenge โ Response and Change and other related speeches,1962 (Box AWS-8)
    - In Times Like These, circa 1937 (Box AWS-8)
    - Introduction of Ambassador Harman, 1963 Feb. 11 (Box AWS-8)
    - Introduction of Brook Hays Platform Guest, 1959 Feb. 15 (Box AWS-8)
    - Introduction of Dr. Hussein Hassouna, Political Counselor of the Embassy of Egypt in Washington, circa 1979-1980 (Box AWS-8)
    - Introduction of His Excellency, Francis A. Dennis, Ambassador of the Republic of Liberia to the United States, Washington, White Rock Baptist Church, 1979 Feb. 25, 2 drafts (Box AWS-8)
    - Introduction of Honorable Maxwell M. Rabb, Secretary to the Cabinet, 1957 Oct. 21 (Box AWS-8)
    - Introduction of J. McNeil Smith at North Carolina College, 1959 May 1 (Box AWS-8)
    - Introduction of Mr. E. M. Debrah White Rock Baptist Church, 1962 Feb. 11 (Box AWS-8)
    - Introduction of Mr. E. M. Martin, 1963 Mar. 1 (Box AWS-8)
    - Is the Future of Private Enterprise Being Jeopardized? press release, 1974 Apr. (Box AWS-8)
    - Is It Better To Be A Dog? (article for Raleigh New and Observer), undated (Box AWS-8)
    - Is Life Worth Living: Does It Pay? undated (Box AWS-8)
    - It Was a Night to Remember, circa 1959 (Box AWS-8)
    - The Key Business of the Modern World Installments I-XV,1938 (Box AWS-8)
    - Kick-Off Message to the Woman-In-Action Coalition for the Reduction of Violence, 1968 Sept. 4, 2 drafts (Box AWS-8)
    - Knowledge is Essential, But Insufficient, address at Langston High School, and related papers, 1962 May and 1980 Nov., Multiple drafts (Box AWS-8)
    - Lack of Appreciation of Negro of Negro Market, undated (Box AWS-8)
    - Laws of Nature May Be Friend or Foe, undated (Box AWS-8)
    - Left Disturbed, press release and related letter regarding Gov. Hunt's decision in the Wilmington 10 case, 1978 Jan. 24, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-8)
    - Legal Interpretation of Policy Contract Clauses, etc., circa 1930s, 2 drafts (Box AWS-8)
    - Let Us Give Thanks, 1964 (Box AWS-9)
    - Letters to the Editor,1970-1980 (Box AWS-9)
    - Life Insurance a Bulwark of the Family and the Nation โ one draft and the newspaper article,1954 (Box AWS-9)
    - Life Insurance A Living Economic Organism and related correspondence [handwritten and typed], circa 1946, 2 drafts (Box AWS-9)
    - Life Insurance Operations Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow from an Actuary's Viewpoint, 1948 June 24, 2 copies (Box AWS-9)
    - Local Communities A Training Ground for World Citizenship, 1957 May? (Box AWS-9)
    - Louis E. Austin: A Man Ahead of His Time, 1971 June 14 (Box AWS-9)
    - A Man of Many Talents Passed This Way! circa 1979. See "Murray J. Marvin: A Man of Talent and Energy." (Box AWS-9)
    - Manager's Function in Risk Selection and Claims, circa 1935 (Box AWS-9)
    - "The Measure of a Man -- Kenneth W. Clement," (eulogy),1974 Dec. 13 (Box AWS-9)
    - Meet the Candidates, 1982 June 24 (Box AWS-9)
    - Meeting Challenges, NC Mutual Managers Advisory Council, 1967 May 18 (Box AWS-9)
    - Meeting the Challenges of the Sixties with Action, keynote address at the Fortieth Annual National Insurance Association Convention, Detroit, Mich.,1960 July 27, 2 drafts (Box AWS-9)
    - A Memorable Day for Me, circa 1960s or 1970s, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-9)
    - A Message of Hope or a Message of Despair, undated (Box AWS-9)
    - A Message: Some Things the North Carolina Mutual Representative Should Know, 1934 Nov. (Box AWS-9)
    - 'Mighty Mo' and Life Insurance, 1950 Oct. (Box AWS-9)
    - Miles Mark Fisher, a Leader of His Flock 1933-1965, 1983 Feb. 13, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-9)
    - Miscellaneous notes for articles and speeches, 1-4 of 8 folders (Box AWS-9)
    - Miscellaneous notes for articles and speeches, 5-8 of 8 folders (Box AWS-10)
    - Moral and Spiritual Values: America's Greatest Need, address delivered at North Carolina College at Durham,1958 Nov. 9, 3 copies (Box AWS-10)
    - The More Abundant Life and related program,1967 May 28, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-10)
    - Mountain Top Experiences, undated (Box AWS-10)
    - Murray Marvin: A Man of Talent and Energy, 1979 Sept. 29 (Box AWS-10)
    - Musings of A. T. Spaulding, 1980 May (Box AWS-10)
    - My Reason for Optimism and Hope, 1972 Dec. 25 and 1973 Jan. 21 (Box AWS-10)
    - The National Newspaper Publishers Association Convention and related work,1966 June 23 (Box AWS-10)
    - "NCM Presidents' Connections With Shaw University," circa 1980 (Box AWS-10)
    - Negro Insurance โ3 different printings,1943, 1946 (Box AWS-10)
    - Negro Insurance in the United States and related correspondence, circa 1943, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-10)
    - Negro Insurance in the United States, working papers,1941-1944 (Box AWS-10)
    - New and Future Contracts, circa 1935, 2 copies (Box AWS-10)
    - The New Life, 1960 (Box AWS-10)
    - Nigerian Ambassador Expresses 'Profound Gratitude' for Two Day Visit to Durham, 1978 May, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-10)
    - 1955 Footprints of North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company, The Whetstone, 1956 1st quarter (Box AWS-10)
    - North Carolina government: color conscious or color blind [untitled],1963 Mar. 23 (Box AWS-10)
    - North Carolina Mutual and the Civil Rights Struggle: A Statement of Company Position, 1967 July 25, 2 drafts (Box AWS-10)
    - North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company.. .A Symbol and related work, circa 1962 (Box AWS-10)
    - North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company and the Durham Community, address to Kiwanis Club of Durham,1967 June 29, 2 drafts (Box AWS-10)
    - No Place for 'Drop-Outs', 1963 Sept. (Box AWS-10)
    - Obituary of Lula Spaulding Jackson, undated (Box AWS-10)
    - O. K., 1937 Aug. (Box AWS-10)
    - The Omitted Asset โ You or You are Important, 1951 Apr. 25 (Box AWS-10)
    - Once-A-Week(Guest editorial in The Wilmington Journal),1979 June 28 (Box AWS-10)
    - One of a Kind, 1979 Nov. 24 (Box AWS-10)
    - On a Mission to Liberia, 1956, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-11)
    - On a Study Tour of West Germany, 1967 Oct. 29-Nov. 12 (Box AWS-11)
    - Opening Pandora's Box: A Management Dilemma, Annual Business Leadership Lecture, Graduate School of Business Administration, The University of Michigan, given upon Spaulding's receipt of school's 1971 Business Leadership Award; and related correspondence and notes,1971, Multiple drafts, 2 folders (Box AWS-11)
    - Opinions on the '70's: North Carolina - South Carolina, 1970 Jan. (Box AWS-11)
    - Opportunities for Fraternities in a Changing Educational World, 1967 Aug. 16 (Box AWS-11)
    - Opportunities for Negro Youth in the Business World, 1949 Apr. 8 (Box AWS-11)
    - Our Environment, 1973 (Box AWS-11)
    - Our Future Lies in Pulling Together, opinion column,Durham Sun, 1979 Oct. 23 [published same day in Durham Morning Herald as What Kind of Leader Do We Want?] (Box AWS-11)
    - Our Heritage, circa 1960s (Box AWS-11)
    - Our Name Plate, 1937 Sept., 2 drafts (Box AWS-11)
    - Outworn Prejudices, (comments by A. T. Spaulding) and related correspondence,1937, 2 drafts (Box AWS-11)
    - Partners in Business, 1940 Nov., 2 copies (Box AWS-11)
    - Pastoral Prayer, circa 1960s (Box AWS-11)
    - A Pathway to Greatness! A Lay Sermon, 1979 Nov. 11 (Box AWS-11)
    - Peddling Your Prunes, 1937 Oct., 2 copies (Box AWS-11)
    - A Personal Approach to the Problems of Racial Equality, circa 1959, 3 drafts (Box AWS-11)
    - Pertinent Executive Problems, 1939 July 12-14, 2 copies (Box AWS-11)
    - Pregnant History Delivers: Launching and Return of Apollo 11! eyewitness account of launch printed in Congressional Record, Senate,1969 Aug. 11 (Box AWS-11)
    - Preliminaries to a Major Construction Job, 1963, 2 drafts (Box AWS-11)
    - Premium Rates, 1935 May 23, 2 drafts [rough and final] (Box AWS-11)
    - "Present Day Challenges to the Business Student and to the Corporation," circa 1964 (Box AWS-11)
    - "President Carter's Hospital Containment Bill," circa 1977-1981 (Box AWS-11)
    - The President Looks at His Job, 1962 Jan. 22 (Box AWS-11)
    - President's Message, undated (Box AWS-11)
    - President's Message: John Moses Avery, My Friend and Comrade, 1951 (Box AWS-11)
    - Proud Parents of a Wise Son, 1977 May 21 (Box AWS-11)
    - Radio Address by Asa T. Spaulding, Candidate for County Commissioner, 1954 June 24 (Box AWS-11)
    - Receiving Key to Branch Office, undated (Box AWS-11)
    - Reflections of Asa T. Spaulding, Sr., Following the Funeral of Godfrey Melvin Herndon on Feb. 17, 1978, Durham Sun, 1978 Feb. 22, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-11)
    - Remarks at President's Home, response by Asa T. Spaulding to presentation by President Cheek at dinner honoring Howard University Honorary Degree recipients,1976 May 7-8 (Box AWS-11)
    - The Report of a Joint Enterprise, 1955, 2 drafts (Box AWS-11)
    - Report to Policyholders, 1961 Jan. 9 (Box AWS-11)
    - Response by Asa T. Spaulding Sr. at 'A Tribute to Dr. Asa T. Spaulding, Sr. 'The Inspiration' and related papers,1981 Feb. 4, 2 drafts (Box AWS-11)
    - Response of Asa T. Spaulding Sr., Recipient of the 50th Anniversary Brotherhood Citation Award, National Conference of Christians and Jews, and related correspondence,1978 June 1, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-11)
    - Response to 'Blacks Break Color Bar in the Board Room', circa 1971 (Box AWS-11)
    - A Retirement Plan for Teachers and related correspondence,1936 Nov., 2 copies (Box AWS-11)
    - Return from Bermuda, 1972 Feb. 21 (Box AWS-11)
    - The Rise to the Presidency and National Attention, 1962 (Box AWS-12)
    - Rising Standards of Living and Future Money Needs, circa 1962, 2 copies (Box AWS-12)
    - Seeking Loftier Heights, undated (Box AWS-12)
    - The Selection of a Candidate for President, 1980 Aug. 19, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-12)
    - Sharing History's Pages with Queens and Kings, circa 1959 (Box AWS-12)
    - The Social Idea in the Settlement of Claims (For release in July Whetstone), undated (Box AWS-12)
    - Some American Profiles in an Age of Challenge, 1958, 3 drafts (Box AWS-12)
    - Some Challenges to Educators, 1965 Apr. 3, 2 drafts (Box AWS-12)
    - Some Effects of Old Age Security Act, undated (Box AWS-12)
    - Some Life Insurance Problems in a Changing Order, circa 1935, 2 copies (Box AWS-12)
    - Some Observations on Organizational Structure and Set-Up of a Mutual Life Insurance Company, undated (Box AWS-12)
    - Some Stages in the Evolution of Life Insurance: A Brief History of its Development in England Prior to 1870 and in the United States since 1759, presented before a class of actuarial students, University of Michigan,1932 Mar. 11, 2 copies (Box AWS-12)
    - Some Things the Business Man of Today Should Know, circa 1936 (Box AWS-12)
    - Spaulding Attends Reception for President Toure: Twenty Years Later โ Spaulding Greets President Toure Again, circa 1979 (Box AWS-12)
    - Spaulding Commends Governor But Sees Disappointment, undated (Box AWS-12)
    - Spaulding Comments on Negro Revolt, 1966 Sept. 15 (Box AWS-12)
    - Spaulding on 'Black-Power' notes, articles, and clippings,1966-1967 (Box AWS-12)
    - Spaulding Speaks to Black Insurance Executives, 1979 July 15-19 (Box AWS-12)
    - Spaulding's Comment on the President's Summit Speech, undated, 2 drafts (Box AWS-12)
    - A Statement before the House of Representative Committee on Un-American Activities, 1967 Oct. 25 (Box AWS-12)
    - A Statement by Asa T. Spaulding, Sr., Candidate for Mayor and Statement II by Asa T. Spaulding, Sr., Candidate for Mayor, 1971 May 3-4 (Box AWS-12)
    - A Statement by Asa T. Spaulding, Sr. of Durham, NC before the House Foreign Affairs Committee in the Rayburn House Building, 1979 Sept. 21 (Box AWS-12)
    - Statement of Asa T. Spaulding at the Retirement Program, 1967 Dec. 29 (Box AWS-12)
    - Stopping Leaks by Paying Attention to the 'Little Things' That Count, 1937 July, 2 drafts (Box AWS-12)
    - Sunday School Lessons and Sermons [Heard by Asa Spaulding], undated, 2 folders (Box AWS-12)
    - The Symbol of a Triumphant Faith, undated (Box AWS-12)
    - Taking the Tide After the Flood (for release in Aug.Whetstone), undated (Box AWS-12)
    - To: All my Co-Workers and Friends, Thank You Very Much! 1959, 2 drafts (Box AWS-12)
    - To the Citizens of Durham County, 1970 Dec. (Box AWS-12)
    - To the Voters of Durham County and related work,1980 Apr. 29, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-12)
    - The Total City concept of Asa T. Spaulding, candidate for Mayor (Box AWS-12)
    - The Tree of Life Insurance and Its Fruits and related works,1953 Sept. 21, Multiple drafts, 2 folders (Box AWS-12)
    - Trees Die at the Top โ So Do Many Business Organizations, undated (Box AWS-12)
    - A Tribute to Hubert Horatio Humphrey, 1978 Jan. 15, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-13)
    - A Tribute to John Fitzgerald Kennedy and In Memoriam: John Fitzgerald Kennedy, 1963 Nov. 23 and 25 (Box AWS-13)
    - A Tribute to a Worthy Pioneer: Conrad O. Pearson, 1979 Aug. 7, 2 drafts (Box AWS-13)
    - A True Story and related program,1964 Apr. 17 (Box AWS-13)
    - Two Intertwined and Interwoven Sagas, undated (Box AWS-13)
    - UNESCO: What Is It, What It Does, and How it Works, 1957 Jan. 15, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-13)
    - United States Delegation Report and related works,1955-1956 (Box AWS-13)
    - Untitled Manuscript about A. T. Spaulding's visit to Bulgaria written by him, undated (Box AWS-13)
    - Upward Thrust, undated (Box AWS-13)
    - An Urge to Self-Improvement, circa 1935 (Box AWS-13)
    - Wanted: Housing Money, International Commerce, 1964 Sept. 14 (Box AWS-13)
    - Wanted! More George Leigh-Mallorys: There Are So Many Mount Everests, Commencement Address at Dillard University, New Orleans,1959 June 1, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-13)
    - Watch the Accent, 1937 Nov. (Box AWS-13)
    - Welcome โ On the Occasion of the Formal Dedication of the New Home Office Building, 1966 Apr. 2 (Box AWS-13)
    - Welcome to Ground-breaking Ceremonies for NC Mutual Life Insurance Company's New Home Office Building and another Ground-breaking ceremony speech,1963 May 17 (Box AWS-13)
    - Welcome to President Sekou Toure and related article,1959 Oct. 29 (Box AWS-13)
    - Welcome to 17th Annual Sales Convention, 1961 Feb. 16 (Box AWS-13)
    - A Welcome to Society of Debutantes and related correspondence,1966, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-13)
    - What Kind of Leader Do We Want?, opinion column,Durham Morning Herald, 1979 Oct. 23 [published same day in Durham Sun as Our Future Lies in Pulling Together] (Box AWS-13)
    - What Price Mortality!, circa 1934 (Box AWS-13)
    - What Seek Ye? circa 1937, 2 drafts (Box AWS-13)
    - What Will Be Our Attitude?, 1943 (Box AWS-13)
    - Where Are the Nine?, circa 1960s (Box AWS-13)
    - Which Is the Better Way, Durham?, 1979 Oct. 19 (Box AWS-13)
    - Which Way America, In Our Race-Relations Dilemma? 1972 Feb. 13, 2 drafts (Box AWS-13)
    - Who Was the First Black Actuary in America? undated, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-13)
    - Who Was the Lucky Guy? undated, Multiple drafts (Box AWS-13)
    - Whose Fault Is It?, circa 1933 (Box AWS-13)
    - Why Consider the Negro Vote: 'A Dangerous Political Football'?, undated (Box AWS-13)
    - Why I Am Supporting President Carter for Re-election, 1980 Oct. 11 (Box AWS-13)
    - Why I Support the Nixon-Lodge Ticket, 1960 (Box AWS-13)
    - Wisdom, undated (Box AWS-13)
    - The World We Live In, circa 1950s (Box AWS-13)
    - Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow Keynote Address to the Technicians of the National Insurance Association,1962 Jul. 24 (Box AWS-13)
    - Works by Other Authors. A-Cl, 3 folders (Box AWS-13)
    - Works by Other Authors. Co-J, 5 folders (Box AWS-14)
    - Works by Other Authors. K-Nixon, 6 folders (Box AWS-15)
    - Works by Other Authors. No-S, 7 folders (Box AWS-16)
    - Works by Other Authors. T-Z, 4 folders (Box AWS-17)
  - Organizations Series, 1930-1983 and undated, bulk 1954-1970, 145 boxes
    Material documenting Spaulding's affiliations with a wide variety of activist, business, civic, educational, fraternal, political, and religious organizations. Contains correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, and printed material. Major organizations represented include the American Academy of Achievement, the American Management Association, the Board of Adjustment for the City of Durham, the Chamber of Commerce of the United States, the Durham County Board of Commissioners, Howard University, the Mayor's Committee on Human Relations (Durham), the Mechanics and Farmers Bank, the NAACP, the National Conference of Christians and Jews, the National Industrial Conference Board, the National Urban League, the North Carolina Advisory Committee to the President's Commission on Civil Rights, North Carolina Central University, Omega Psi Phi, the President's Commission on Income Maintenance, Shaw University, UNESCO, the Urban Coalition, the Urban National Corporation, and White Rock Baptist Church. Arranged alphabetically by name of organization.
    - A. T. Spaulding Consulting and Advisory Services,1971 (Box AO-1)
    - Action Housing Inc.,1967 (Box AO-1)
    - Action-In-Manpower,1968 (Box AO-1)
    - Actuarial Science Fellowship Fund,1960 (Box AO-1)
    - Adlai Stevenson Institute,1968 (Box AO-1)
    - Admirals of the Flagship Fleet,1965 (Box AO-1)
    - Advisory Committee to the Youth Opportunity Campaign,1964-1966 (Box AO-1)
    - Afram Continental Corporation,1960-1961, 2 folders (Box AO-1)
    - African-American Students Foundation, Inc.,1959 (Box AO-1)
    - African-American Trade and Development Association, Inc.,1961 (Box AO-1)
    - African Methodist Episcopal Church,1964 (Box AO-1)
    - Afro-American Society,1968 (Box AO-1)
    - Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service, 1967 (Box AO-2)
    - Agricultural and Technical College of North Carolina,1959-1970, 2 folders (Box AO-2)
    - Airline Passengers' Association,1979 (Box AO-2)
    - Alexander Sterling Hunter Lodge,1977 (Box AO-2)
    - Algonquin Tennis Club,1941 (Box AO-2)
    - Alice B. Toklas Democratic Club of Wake County,1980 (Box AO-2)
    - Alliance for Progress,1965-1968 (Box AO-2)
    - Allied Arts of Durham, Inc.,1965-1967 (Box AO-2)
    - Alumni Federation of New York University,1977-1980 (Box AO-2)
    - American Academy of Achievement,1964-1971 and undated, Folder 1 of 12 (Box AO-2)
    - American Academy of Achievement,1964-1971 and undated, Folders 2-9 of 12 (Box AO-3)
    - American Academy of Achievement,1964-1971 and undated, Folders 10-12 of 12 (Box AO-4)
    - American Academy of Actuaries,1965-1983, 2 folders (Box AO-4)
    - The American Academy of Political and Social Science,1968 (Box AO-4)
    - American Arbitration Association,1961-1963 (Box AO-4)
    - American Assembly,1967-1979, 2 folders (Box AO-4)
    - American Association for The United Nations,1957 (Box AO-5)
    - American Association of Individual Investors (Box AO-5)
    - American Association of Retired Persons (Box AO-5)
    - The American Association of University Teachers of Insurance,1959-1961 (Box AO-5)
    - American Baptist ConventionโBenedict College,1956-1959 (Box AO-5)
    - American Bar Association,1957 (Box AO-5)
    - American Biographical Institute (Box AO-5)
    - American Cancer Society,1953-1980 (Box AO-5)
    - American Chemical Society,1965 (Box AO-5)
    - American Civil Liberties Union,1964 (Box AO-5)
    - American Committee on Africa,1959-1967 (Box AO-5)
    - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO),1972-1980 (Box AO-5)
    - American Federation for the Blind,1961 and undated (Box AO-5)
    - American Foundation for Negro Affairs,1968 (Box AO-5)
    - American Freedom Association, 1957 Jan., 2 folders (Box AO-5)
    - American Freedom Forest Dedication Committee,1964-1966 (Box AO-5)
    - American Freedom from Hunger Foundation, Inc.,1957-1967, Folder 1 of 6 (Box AO-5)
    - American Freedom from Hunger Foundation, Inc.,1957-1967, Folders 2-6 of 6 (Box AO-6)
    - American Friends Service Committee,1949-1968 and undated, 2 folders (Box AO-6)
    - The American Heritage Foundation,1957 (Box AO-7)
    - American Institute of Management,1959-1967 and undated, 3 folders (Box AO-7)
    - American Legion,1965-1970 (Box AO-7)
    - American Management Association,1962-1969 and undated, Folders 1-2 of 15 (Box AO-7)
    - American Management Association,1962-1969 and undated, Folders 3-8 of 15 (Box AO-8)
    - American Management Association, 1962-1969 and undated, Folders 9-13 of 15 (Box AO-9)
    - American Management Association,1962-1969 and undated, Folders 14-15 of 15 (Box AO-10)
    - American Mathematical Society,1959-1966 (Box AO-10)
    - American Negro Emancipation Centennial,1956 (Box AO-10)
    - American Negro Leadership Conference on Africa,1964-1968 (Box AO-10)
    - American Red Cross,1934-1951 (Box AO-10)
    - American Security Council,1961 (Box AO-10)
    - American Security Council Education Foundation,1977 (Box AO-10)
    - American Society of African Culture,1959-1962 (Box AO-10)
    - American Statistical Association,1961-1964 (Box AO-10)
    - Americans for Biafran Relief,1969 (Box AO-10)
    - Americans for Democratic Action,1964 (Box AO-10)
    - Annual Reports of Corporations,1962-1973, Folders 1-2 of 11 (Box AO-10)
    - Annual Reports of Corporations,1962-1973, Folders 3-8 of 11 (Box AO-11)
    - Annual Reports of Corporations,1962-1973, Folders 9-11 of 11 (Box AO-12)
    - A. Philip Randolph Institute,1969-1971, 2 folders (Box AO-12)
    - Asa T. Spaulding Association (ATSA) Journal,1983 (Box AO-12)
    - Asa T. Spaulding Insurance Society, 3 folders (Box AO-12)
    - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies,1980 (Box AO-12)
    - Association of Governing Boards of Universities and Colleges,1969 (Box AO-12)
    - Association for the Integration of Management, Inc.,1971-1982 (Box AO-13)
    - Association Internationale des Estudiants en Sciences Economiques et Commercials,1962-1966 (Box AO-13)
    - Association of Social Science Teachers in Negro Schools,1948-1952 (Box AO-13)
    - Association for the study of Negro Life and History, Inc.,1962-1968 (Box AO-13)
    - Atlanta Secretarial League,1964 (Box AO-13)
    - The Atlantic Council of the United States,1977 (Box AO-13)
    - AVCO Corporation,1972 (Box AO-13)
    - Joseph V. Baker Associates, Inc.,1961 (Box AO-13)
    - Baptist Leader,1980 (Box AO-13)
    - Beta Gamma Sigma,1942-1968 (Box AO-13)
    - Black Economic Development Corporation, Inc.,1969, 2 folders (Box AO-13)
    - Black Solidarity Committee,1969 (Box AO-13)
    - Board of Adjustment, City of Durham,1955-1968 and undated, Folders 1-4 of 19 (Box AO-13)
    - Board of Adjustment, City of Durham,1955-1968 and undated, Folders 5-12 of 19 (Box AO-14)
    - Board of Adjustment, City of Durham,1955-1968 and undated, Folders 13-19 of 19 (Box AO-15)
    - Booker T. Washington Memorial Foundation,1948 (Box AO-15)